Every day I wake up in the morning and nothing gets me
每天早上醒來
more excited than changing the same pixel values.
最讓我興奮的事情莫過於連續更改 20 次相同的畫素值
20 times in a row to make me feel like I'm doing a huge valuable service to mankind.
讓我覺得自己在為人類做了一件非常有價值的事。
And since you guys are CSS experts according to my community post,
既然你們是 css 專家，根據我的社群帖子
I want to fulfill your lifelong ambition of becoming a CSS rock star.
我想滿足你們成為 CSS 搖滾明星的畢生抱負。
In this CSS layout guide, it's not about explaining every possible CSS property and value.
在這本 CSS 佈局指南中，我並不是要解釋 CSS 的所有屬性和值。
because there are a ton of resources out there that can tell you how to do that.
因為有大量資源可以告訴你如何做到這一點。
However, I want to mention how you should approach and think in CSS so that your CSS isn't
不過，我想說的是，你應該如何處理和思考 CSS 佈局
Now this works with any kind of CSS library, post processors, or components.
這適用於任何 CSS 庫、後處理器或元件。
or anything you can think of, because it's more about the approach.
或者你能想到的任何東西，因為它更多的是關於方法。
Now there's some rare articles that will explain what I'm talking about.
現在有一些罕見的文章可以解釋我所說的內容。
But I want to cover that in the video and go further on how you can approach every little step.
但我想在影片中進一步介紹如何處理每一個小步驟。
So when you are given a design that you need to implement with CSS,
所以，當你得到一個需要用 CSS 來實現的設計時、
The very first thing you should be doing is visualizing everything in terms of boxes.
你應該做的第一件事，就是用方框的形式將一切視覺化。
And to start with, we want to talk about the CSS box model.
首先，我們要談談 CSS 框模型。
So the CSS box model represents all the layers, a single box.
CSS 框模型代表了所有的層，即一個單獨的框。
So we include content, padding, border.
因此，我們包括內容、padding、邊框。
in margin and by default css sets everything to be content box which you
預設情況下，CSS 將所有內容都設定為內容框。
only includes content.
只包含內容。
So that represents one element.
因此，這就代表了一個元素。
But if you set it to border box, you include the padding and the border.
但如果設定為 border box，就會包含 padding 和 border。
So once you understand the box model, now we can split our layout into different blocks.
瞭解了盒子模型之後，我們就可以將佈局分割成不同的區塊了。
and we want to be able to visualize every element on the page as a block.
我們希望能將頁面上的每個元素都視覺化為一個塊。
As you can see here, we start from the outside and then we go inside.
正如你在這裡看到的，我們從外部開始，然後進入內部。
And we always start from the top and we go horizontally.
我們總是從頂部開始橫向佈局。
We don't go vertically because divs naturally stack on top of each other.
我們不會縱向排列，因為 div 會自然地疊加在一起。
So we want to make sure we start horizontally splitting the elements.
因此，我們要確保從水平方向開始分割元素。
into different blocks.
分成不同的塊。
Now, for example, if we take the YouTube landing page.
現在，以 YouTube 登陸頁面為例。
We can toggle this Chrome extension, which will allow us to see all the elements
我們可以切換 Chrome 瀏覽器擴充套件，這樣就可以將頁面上的所有元素
on this page as different boxes.
以不同的方框顯示。
So if you hover over this, we see the nav bar.
因此，如果將滑鼠懸停在這裡，我們會看到導航欄。
We have another box over here as here and here.
這裡還有一個方框，這裡和這裡也是。
as well as each of the videos are a box in itself.
每個影片本身也是一個方框。
And now you can imagine if you're using a framework, visualizing these boxes also helps.
現在你可以想象，如果你使用的是框架，視覺化這些方框也會有所幫助。
set up the components that you would need for something like React Vue.
如果你使用的是 React Vue 這樣的框架，視覺化這些方框也會有所幫助。
Angular or Svelte so these components are perfect
Angular 或 Svelte 等框架所需的元件，因此這些元件非常適合
for those boxes.
因此這些元件非常適合這些盒子。
And as we've seen with some of the layouts,
正如我們在一些佈局中看到的那樣、
Some of the most important things to understand is that everything...
需要了解的最重要的一點是，一切...
has a parent-child relationship.
都有父子關係。
So every element here has both a parent
所以這裡的每個元素都有父
and a child.
和子元素。
will be very key to understanding how we can use Flexbox and Grid
這對我們理解如何使用 Flexbox 和 Grid
for a lot of our layouts.
佈局的關鍵。
Now visualizing
現在視覺化
or layouts via blocks really helps.
或透過塊進行佈局真的很有幫助。
set the foundation and the structure of our entire CSS code.
它為我們的整個 CSS 程式碼奠定了基礎和結構。
and that helps us utilize a very important tool that we know as Flexbox.
這有助於我們利用一個非常重要的工具，我們稱之為 Flexbox。
Now there are several tools for positioning things on the website.
現在，網站上有多種定位工具。
But the number one tool you should always reach for is going to be Flexbox.
但你最應該使用的工具是 Flexbox。
There's another tool called float that you can use to
還有一個叫 float 的工具，可以用來
position things, but it is the outdated way of positioning and you should only use it if you.
但它是過時的定位方式，只有在你需要的時候才可以使用。
When it comes to Flexbox vs Absolute Positioning, a lot of people
說到 Flexbox 與絕對定位，很多人
tend to use absolute positioning as their default method, which I believe is a basic mistake.
我認為這是一個基本錯誤。
And there are a few reasons why.
原因有以下幾點。
First off, it's harder on responsive design.
首先，它更難實現響應式設計。
For example, if you have something that's set to 150 pixel.
舉例來說，如果你將某項內容設定為 150 畫素。
from the right side of the screen, it's going
從螢幕右側看，它會
to be in a very drastically different position for a screen of 3000 pixels.
在 3000 畫素的螢幕上的位置就會大不相同。
versus a mobile screen which is 300 pixel where 150 pixels from the right would
與 300 畫素的移動螢幕相比，右側 150 畫素的位置將
would be in the center.
將位於中央。
And on top of that, that leads to you designing in a specific pixel.
除此之外，這還會導致你在設計時採用特定的畫素。
perfect manner, which is not ideal.
完美的方式進行設計，這並不理想。
Now there's a bigger reason why you should always use flexbox vs absolute positioning and that's because
現在還有一個更大的原因，那就是你應該始終使用柔性框與絕對定位，這是因為
Flexbox does not disturb the flow of the layout.
柔性框不會干擾佈局的流程。
What that means is that if you take a look at this layout and you look at this nav bar,
這意味著，如果你看看這個佈局，再看看這個導航欄，你就會發現，Flexbox 並不會影響佈局的流暢性、
Every item is in relation to each other.
每個專案都是相互關聯的。
For example, this item
例如，這個專案
is related to this because they're on the same line and they're kind of positioned to the right.
與此相關，因為它們位於同一行，而且位置靠右。
However, if you take a look at this, this night time...
但是，如果你看一下這個，這個夜間時間......
icon and you remove it what happens is none of these other items
圖示，並將其移除，那麼這些其他專案就都不存在了
move which is not ideal sometimes you do not want this big of a space between these two items
有時您不希望在這兩個專案之間留出這麼大的空間。
And let's actually also take out this profile.
實際上，我們還可以把這個輪廓去掉。
And now we just have a big gap between these items and this.
現在，這些專案和這個專案之間有了很大的空隙。
requires us to position this and move this over here.
這就需要我們定位這個，把它移到這裡。
here which is quite the hassle.
這就很麻煩了。
In contrast, let's look at Flexbox.
相比之下，我們來看看 Flexbox。
We have these items again and let's see what happens when we take out these settings.
我們又有了這些專案，讓我們看看去掉這些設定後會發生什麼。
We can see that this has been moved over along with this.
我們可以看到，這個和這個一起被移到了這裡。
And then let's actually take out the profile icon.
然後，讓我們實際移除配置檔案圖示。
And as you can see, it's been moved, aligned over here.
正如你所看到的，它被移到了這裡，與這裡對齊。
So it's very easy to have it set up in a way that we would like.
因此，我們很容易就能按照自己的喜好進行設定。
way easier because we are following the flow of the layout.
因為我們是按照佈局的流程來設定的。
They have a relationship.
它們之間是有關係的。
where with the other positions of each item is.
每個專案的其他位置在哪裡。
So even in the search bar,
因此，即使在搜尋欄中也是如此、
This is positioned to the right of this along with the search which is on the left side.
這個位置在右邊，搜尋在左邊。
So there's always this flow dynamic with a lot of items on.
因此，在頁面上有很多專案時，總會有這樣的動態流程。
page and for that reason having Flexbox.
因此，使用 Flexbox
it's way easier to maintain.
更容易維護。
If you've ever tried to
如果你曾經試圖
fix up a code base where everything's absolutely positioned.
如果你曾經試圖修復一個程式碼庫，其中的所有內容都是絕對定位的。
you'll start to realize this becomes a nightmare to maintain.
你就會意識到這將成為維護工作的噩夢。
because you have to constantly calculate pixels.
因為你必須不斷地計算畫素。
Flexbox is the ideal tool
Flexbox 是理想的工具
when it comes to most applications and most websites.
當涉及到大多數應用程式和大多數網站時。
Now Flexbox has a lot of properties going on with it.
現在，Flexbox 有很多特性。
but there's actually only a few properties that you really need to know.
但實際上，真正需要了解的屬性只有幾個。
And it's very important to understand that.
理解這一點非常重要。
parent-child relationships I mentioned before.
我之前提到的父子關係。
because you're going to use different properties on the parent element.
因為你要在父元素上使用不同的屬性。
of all the children in Flexbox.
因為你要在 Flexbox 中的所有子元素上使用不同的屬性。
So the parent attributes are going to have all of these properties you see here.
因此，父元素屬性將擁有你在這裡看到的所有屬性。
but the ones that we concern ourselves is just gonna be
但我們關心的只是
display, justify content, and align.
display、justify content 和 align。
Items these three properties are the only properties that you really need to know
這三個屬性是你真正需要知道的屬性
and even with justified content and aligned items.
即使是對齊內容和對齊專案。
There's only a few properties of each of those.
每個屬性都只有幾個。
Xbox, it is very handy to have a cheat sheet at your disposal.
有了小抄，你在使用 Xbox 時就會得心應手。
utilize this to see and visualize what these properties are doing.
利用它，你可以看到並直觀地瞭解這些屬性的作用。
justify-content is going to be the most commonly used Flexbox parent property that you will
JustifyContent 將是最常用的 Flexbox 父屬性，您將
need to use.
需要使用的屬性。
And justify-content aligns the items or the children
正當化內容將專案或子專案
in a horizontal direction or whichever direction is the default.
以水平方向或預設方向對齊。
So we have flex-start, flex-end, center, space between, and then space around.
因此，我們有 Flex start、Flex end、center、space between 和 space around。
So space between, space around, center are the most
最常用的是中間空格、四周空格和居中。
common and then occasionally you will use flex start flex end.
間距、左右間距、居中是最常用的，偶爾也會用到彈性開始、彈性結束。
And then the second most commonly used alignment.
第二種最常用的對齊方式
is going to be align content which is
對齊內容
Pretty much the same thing as justify-content, but it's going to align things vertically.
與 justify-content 差不多，但它是垂直對齊。
So we have flex-start, flex-end, center, space between, and space around.
因此，我們有了 flex-start、flex-end、center、space-between 和 space around。
The most commonly one you're going to be using is going to be center because
最常用的是居中，因為
a lot of times we're just going to align one horizontal line.
因為很多時候我們只需對齊一條水平線。
So even in a basic example, you can see that this is flex right here.
因此，即使是在一個基本的例子中，你也可以看到這裡是柔性的。
And then we're using space between for this particular div, spacing everything out.
然後我們在這個特殊的 div 之間使用空格，將所有內容間隔開來。
And then same thing over here, this is another parent.
這裡也是一樣，這是另一個父代。
And then these are the child with these navigation items.
然後這些是帶有導航項的子代。
and these are doing space between.
這些都是空格。
Note that
注意
that up here, we're also vertically aligning them.
在這裡，我們還對它們進行了垂直對齊。
So we're using line content center.
因此，我們使用的是行內容居中。
So this is one of the most common ways you can use Flex to set up your...
這就是使用 Flex 設定佈局的最常見方法之一。
Layouts and now there's another property you can use flex-wrap
佈局的最常用方法之一。
but I'm going to show you ways so that you don't ever need to use flex-wrap.
但我要向您展示的是，您無需使用 flex-wrap 的方法。
Now when it comes to the child properties of Flexbox,
現在來看看 Flexbox 的子屬性、
There's only a few properties that you really have to know and you're only going to use it occasionally.
只有少數幾個屬性是你必須知道的，而且只是偶爾會用到。
So flex-grow for example is if you set this to be zero it's going to take up
例如，如果將其設定為零，flex-grow 將佔用
the amount of space that you would normally expect it to, but if you click on one.
空間，但如果你點選 "1"。
It's going to grow as much as possible if there's extra space.
如果有多餘的空間，它會盡可能多地增長。
in this element.
在這個元素中。
And we also have flex-basis, so
我們還有彈性底座，所以
It's very complex on what flex-basis does over width.
flex-basis 對寬度的處理非常複雜
but it's basically the same thing as width with a...
但它與寬度基本上是一樣的。
few additional properties and that interacts better with Flexbox.
只是多了一些屬性，而且與 Flexbox 的互動更好。
Now I'm going to leave a link in the description if you want to go in depth about
我有在描述放了一個連結，如果你想深入瞭解 flex-basis
flex bases, but you should always flex bases over width when you're using Flexbox.
但在使用 Flexbox 時，你應該使用 flex-basis，而不是 width。
So flex is good for situations like this where there's
因此，Flex 非常適合像這樣有
one dimension, meaning it's either horizontal or vertical.
一個維度，即水平或垂直。
but if you have a section where it's kinda like this
但如果有一個部分有點像這樣
where there is both horizontal and vertical elements.
既有水平元素又有垂直元素。
then grid is the better option.
那麼網格就是更好的選擇。
Now even in a situation like this where we just have a list of items displayed in a gallery like format.
即使在這種情況下，我們只是以類似相簿的格式顯示專案列表。
But grid is still pretty very easy to implement and we can just do this in three lines of
但網格仍然非常容易實現，我們只需三行
code.
程式碼就能實現。
However, if we try to use flex, there's actually a problem with using flex in this case.
但是，如果我們嘗試使用 flex，在這種情況下使用 flex 實際上會有一個問題。
we tend to have no problems with the first line but the second line where we have
第一行沒有問題，但第二行就有問題了。
not three items, we have two items.
不是三個專案，而是兩個專案。
This becomes a problem.
這就成了一個問題。
We cannot fix this without some hacky workaround.
如果不採取一些笨辦法，我們就無法解決這個問題。
So let's take a look at another example.
因此，我們來看另一個例子。
pretty simple layout.
非常簡單的佈局。
This is a common magazine type layout.
這是一種常見的雜誌式佈局。
And over here, we have the code that represents this type of grid.
在這裡，我們有代表這種網格型別的程式碼。
And now if you take a look with the flex, you're going to have to set this flex into two.
現在，如果你看一下柔性，你將不得不把這個柔性設定為兩個。
separate sections and then over here this would be
分開，然後這裡是
the entire width and this would be half of that width.
是整個寬度，而這裡是寬度的一半。
Compare that with grid.
與網格比較一下。
This will produce the exact same results right here.
這將產生完全相同的結果。
It's just the code will now be much cleaner.
只是程式碼變得更簡潔了。
Now grid is very scary at first because there's so many different options and there's so many different
一開始，網格是非常可怕的，因為有太多不同的選項，有太多不同的
ways to go about using Grid, but I want
方法，但我想
to show you a very simple step-by-step guide on how to approach Grid and there's not
但我想向你展示一個非常簡單的分步指南，告訴你如何使用網格。
a lot of things you actually have to know.
你必須知道的東西其實並不多。
So the first step
所以第一步
in understanding grid is that we want to split it into the smallest
我們要把網格分割成最小的
divisible unit for columns.
列。
So if we take a look
因此，如果我們看一看
At this example, this particular section where we have this huge grid.
在這個例子中，我們有一個巨大的網格。
and we have different varying sizes of boxes, we can take a look at this first row.
我們可以看看第一行。
So we can try and split this into 1 unit, 2 unit, 3 unit.
我們可以嘗試將其分為 1 個單元、2 個單元、3 個單元。
four unit because these are small boxes we can say there's four columns in this particular grid.
4個單位，因為這些都是小方框，我們可以說這個網格中有四列。
But the problem is if we take a look at this bottom box.
但問題是，如果我們看一下最下面的這個方框。
This is not going to fit neatly into those
它並不能整齊地放入這些
particular four columns because this kind of overlaps if you take a look right here.
因為如果你看一下這裡的話，它會重疊在一起。
this finishes three fourths of the way of this particular box.
這個方框的四分之三。
So it doesn't
所以它不能
neatly fit into that unit.
整齊地放入那個單元。
So what we can do...
所以我們可以...
instead is going to divide this into smaller amount of units and we can say this will be
就是把它分成更小的單位，我們可以說這將是
3 units, so each of these box will be 3 units.
3個單位，所以每個盒子就是3個單位。
So that would be a total of 12 columns across.
這樣一共有 12 列。
And then we can say this bottom one is now going to be four columns.
然後我們可以說，最下面這一列現在將是四列。
And if we could click on this, we can now see
點選這裡，我們可以看到
that this first box represents three columns.
第一個方框代表三列。
and this bottom box represents four columns.
而底部這個方框代表四列。
So that will now work out with this particular grid and then we can also check
這樣，這個網格就能正常工作了，然後我們還可以選中
the middle one and this will be 8 units across.
然後我們還可以選中中間的方框，這樣就可以橫跨 8 個單位了。
And now we can also take a look at the rows.
現在我們還可以看看行。
So if we take a look, we're going to have
如果我們看一下，我們將有
five units of rows vertically.
5 個單位的垂直行。
So the first row is going to just be one unit.
所以第一行只有一個單位。
but then the second row is going to involve two units and the last one is also going to be two units.
第二行是兩個單元，最後一行也是兩個單元。
So that means what we have set up.
也就是說，我們所設定的
for our grid is that we now have 12 columns of units.
我們的網格現在有 12 列單位。
and then five rows of units.
然後是五行單位。
And that is what we're going to be using
這就是我們要用來
to set up our grid.
來設定我們的網格。
the level of complexity of the design.
設計的複雜程度
we are going to use different methods for grids.
我們將使用不同的方法來設定網格。
in three different scenarios and I'm going to go through and walk through each type.
我們將在三種不同的場景中使用不同的網格方法，下面我將逐一介紹。
Now going back to our admin dashboard, I would
現在回到我們的管理儀表板，我會
Consider this a medium level of complexity when we use GRID.
當我們使用 GRID 時，將其視為中等複雜程度。
The way I determined that is most of the items there is some consistency.
我確定這一點的方法是，大多數專案在方框尺寸上都有一定的一致性。
in the box sizings.
但也有一些差異。
So we are going to...
因此，我們要...
specify each item and we're going to give each item their own level of units.
指定每個專案，並賦予每個專案各自的單位級別。
So the way we start is setting the parent to be display of grid.
因此，我們首先要將父項設定為顯示網格。
and then we can use grid template column.
然後我們可以使用網格模板列。
So this is going to be the most commonly used property
這將是最常用的屬性
that you'll end up using.
最常用的屬性。
And you're going to need to get familiar with
你需要熟悉
the repeat function inside here.
裡面的 repeat 函式。
And all this means
這意味著
is that we're setting up this to be 12 columns like we mentioned before.
就是我們要設定成 12 列，就像我們之前提到的那樣。
and we are going to set each column
我們要將每一列
with the size of one fractional unit.
設定為一個小數單位。
Now you can set this to be pixels and you can change this up depending on what you want.
現在，你可以將其設定為畫素，也可以根據自己的需要進行更改。
but here this is pretty simple so that means we're just dividing
但這裡的設定非常簡單，也就是說，我們只需將
based on the number of units that this row has.
基於這一行的單位數。
So, it is one fractional unit for 12 different columns.
因此，12 個不同的列都是一個小數單位。
So this is basically the width of each column and this is the total number of columns.
這就是每一列的寬度和列的總數。
And then for the rows, we have grid auto rows.
對於行，我們有網格自動行。
So that means each row in this case, we're not using.
也就是說，在這種情況下，我們不會使用每一行。
template rows so we don't use
模板行，所以我們不使用
units, we're actually setting this to be 150 pixels.
單位，我們實際上將其設定為 150 畫素。
So that means this particular row is 150.
因此，這意味著這一行是 150 畫素。
and since this is two units this is going to be three hundred and
由於這是兩個單位，因此這一行的畫素將是 300
300 pixels right here for this particular box.
300 畫素。
And we also set a gap of 20 pixels.
我們還設定了 20 畫素的間距。
That just means 20 pixels spacing in between.
這意味著中間的間距為 20 畫素。
And then from here, it's pretty simple.
從這裡開始，就非常簡單了。
So we can now set the first box
現在我們可以設定第一個方框
it's going to be a span of three.
它的跨度為 3。
We don't need to set
我們不需要將
grid row to be span of one because that's what it is by default.
網格行的跨度為一，因為預設情況就是這樣。
But if we take a look and we go down and we go to row two.
但如果我們看一下，然後向下移動到第二行。
We now have a grid column of span of 8, which represents this particular guy.
現在我們有了一個跨度為 8 的網格列，它代表了這個特殊的人。
and then we set a span of 2 for the rows.
然後我們再將行的跨度設定為 2。
And then this, as you can guess, is going to be a span of four.
然後，正如你所猜測的那樣，這一行的跨度為 4。
and a grid row span of two.
網格行跨度為 2。
And now you can see
現在你可以看到
that this is going to be grid column span of three with a span of two rows.
網格列跨度為 3，行跨度為 2。
And as you can see, this is pretty simple once you have that unit layout.
正如你所看到的，一旦有了單元佈局，這就非常簡單了。
for each column and the number of rows.
每列和每行的行數。
you can easily set the specified spans to be what you
你可以很容易地將指定的跨度設定為你想要的跨度。
want exactly it just takes a little
你可以很容易地將指定的跨度設定成你想要的樣子。
bit of effort dividing the number of columns.
只需將列數
and the number of rows but once you have that you have very good control
但一旦你有了這些，你就能很好地控制
of how much space each element is going to take.
每個元素將佔用多少空間。
Now before we were doing admin that had a very consistent level of
現在，我們在做管理之前，有一個非常一致的
boxes so there is a little bit of symmetry and
方框，所以有一點對稱和
consistency with that layout.
一致性。
But this one right here...
但這裡的這個...
we have boxes that span different vertical elements.
我們有橫跨不同垂直元素的方框。
And I would consider that
我認為
in a situation where this becomes an advanced complexity for grid.
這將成為網格的高階複雜性。
and that's where we are going to use grid template areas.
這就是我們要使用網格模板區域的地方。
and grid template areas gives us maximum full control and an
網格模板區域為我們提供了最大程度的全面控制和一個
It also allows us to maintain this type of CSS code very easily.
它還能讓我們輕鬆維護這類 CSS 程式碼。
So the way we do this is we're going to set our columns and the rows as usual.
因此，我們要做的就是像往常一樣設定列和行。
Most importantly, we are setting grid template areas.
最重要的是，我們要設定網格模板區域。
So the way this works is that instead
這樣做的方式是
of giving each box or element inside the grid
而不是給網格內的每個框或元素
a specific length and height.
指定長度和高度。
We are instead
而是
specifying kind of like a mini-map.
而是指定一種類似小地圖
or diagram of sorts to identify where things go in the grid.
或類似圖表的方式來確定網格中的位置。
So, for example, AAA, these are consistent, that represents
例如，AAA，這些是一致的，表示
this particular box over here.
這個特定的方框。
So A represents this particular element.
所以 A 代表這個特定的元素。
B represents this one and then C represents this one.
B 代表這個，然後 C 代表這個。
So C is three
所以 C 是三個
Units vertically and we can see these over here, and this would be
垂直單位，我們可以在這裡看到這些，這將是
three units vertically, E would be two units vertically, and then F would be three units vertically.
垂直方向上是三個單位，E 垂直方向上是兩個單位，F 垂直方向上是三個單位。
but this one would overlap on the fourth row.
但這個會在第四行重疊。
and we can continue doing the same with g g g and then h h h would be
我們可以用 g g g 繼續做同樣的操作，然後 h h h 將是
four units vertically with ii and jj.
與 ii 和 jj 在垂直方向上是四個單元。
So that allows us to control these elements.
這樣，我們就可以控制這些元素了。
And the way we identify each box is
我們識別每個方框的方法是
is we're going to call this grid area.
我們將其稱為網格區域。
So now all we have to do is we can go to our
現在我們要做的就是進入我們的
box and go down and specify this is a
框，然後指定這是一個
a custom component that I created, but this is grid area A.
我建立的自定義元件，但這是網格區域 A。
that represents this particular section, and then grid area B represents this, and C represents
網格區域 B 代表這個區域，網格區域 C 代表這個區域，網格區域 D 代表這個區域，網格區域 E 代表這個區域。
that.
那個。
So now we don't actually have to worry about the order of the elements when we play
因此，現在我們在玩
place in the components, we can just set this
放置元件時，我們只需將其設定為適當的網格區域。
to be the proper grid area.
作為適當的網格區域。
I could call this C instead if I wanted to.
如果我願意，也可以把它叫做 C。
And that would just make this one particular C. We could change this like that.
我們可以這樣更改。
and that would just change it up like this so we would replace those
這樣我們就可以替換掉這些
items.
專案。
So as you can see, it can be a very easy swap with this type of layout.
因此，正如你所看到的，這種型別的佈局可以很容易地互換。
And then we would continue doing the same thing for D, E, F, and then G, H, and D.
然後，我們將繼續對 D、E、F 以及 G、H 和 D 進行同樣的操作。
And with that, we would have our grid template area for our entire screen.
這樣，整個螢幕就有了網格模板區域。
So I highly recommend using grid template areas when you have a when you basically have
因此，我強烈推薦大家使用網格模板區域。
chaos in your layouts.
佈局混亂時，我強烈推薦使用網格模板區域。
Now this is kind of an exception, this last type
現在這是一個例外，最後一種型別的
of GridLayout, you actually didn't need to setup
網格佈局，你實際上不需要設定
The smallest divisible unit for columns and rows for this type of situation
這種情況下的列和行的最小可分割單位
which is when you have something like this as you see in this e-commerce website.
就像你在這個電子商務網站中看到的那樣。
This is when all the items or all the children.
這時所有的專案或所有的子項。
are basically the same width and the same height.
基本上是同寬同高。
So we don't actually need to set up.
因此，我們實際上不需要設定
the width or the height or the number of columns or the number of rows.
寬度、高度、列數或行數。
And the way we do this is we just set this to display to be
我們這樣做的方法是，只需將顯示設定為
grid and we can set grid template columns to repeat.
網格，並將網格模板列設定為重複。
and we can set this to be autofill.
我們還可以將其設定為自動填充。
So it determines the number of columns
因此，它決定了列數
for us, and we set each column to be 300 pixels.
我們將每列設定為 300 畫素。
and we can say justify content space around that determines how
我們可以說，周圍的內容空間決定了
the items are going to be laid out.
項的佈局。
So even in this case...
因此，即使在這種情況下...
Everything is completely responsive without us doing
所有內容都是完全響應的，無需進行
any kind of media queries, which is very, very nice.
任何媒體查詢，這非常非常好。
And just to note, on the children we don't have to specify anything at all.
需要注意的是，在子專案上，我們根本不需要指定任何東西。
And that's how you should approach grid.
這就是你應該如何處理網格。
You shouldn't approach by learning all the properties.
你不應該學習所有的屬性。
you should actually approach it by following a step-by-step guide on how to use it.
實際上，你應該透過一步步學習如何使用它。
which is much easier, not fortunately, with Flexbox.
有了 Flexbox，這就容易多了，而不是幸運。
and css grid if you manage to do these
和 css 網格，如果你能正確地做到這些
correctly, it'll minimize the number of media queries you would have to write.
和 css 網格，就能最大限度地減少需要編寫的媒體查詢次數。
Now if you take a look at this example, this particular website is mostly done with Flex.
現在，如果你看一下這個例子，這個網站主要是用 Flex 完成的。
So if you have a larger screen, we go to medium size screens.
因此，如果你的螢幕較大，我們就使用中型螢幕。
and most of it is responsive.
而且大部分都是響應式的。
So a lot of this will be properly fit.
所以很多內容都能很好地融入到設計中。
into the design and we don't have to deal with a lot of media queries for medium-sized screens.
我們不必為中型螢幕處理大量的媒體查詢。
Now we still do have to use media queries for smaller screens so if we go to
現在，我們仍然需要為較小的螢幕使用媒體查詢，所以如果我們轉到
this size as you can see these elements
這個尺寸，你可以看到這些元素
have stacked on top of each other.
會堆疊在一起。
But fortunately, if we're using Flexbox or Grid, it is quite simple.
不過幸運的是，如果我們使用的是 Flexbox 或 Grid，就會非常簡單。
all we have to do for example in this particular section where there is
我們要做的就是，例如在這個特殊的部分，有
three elements and this is flex with space between.
三個元素，這就是在中間留出空間的 Flexbox。
All we have to do in the media query is remove the flex.
我們在媒體查詢中要做的就是移除 Flex。
and they'll naturally stack on top of each other.
然後它們就會自然地堆疊在一起。
And this is a common pattern that you can do
這是一種常見的模式，你可以這樣做
for a lot of different situations where we have flex over here.
很多不同的情況。
And all we have to do is remove that flex when the screen has gotten small enough.
我們所要做的就是在螢幕足夠小的時候移除撓性部分。
where it's reasonable.
這樣就比較合理了。
Now sometimes you do have to do some experimentation to figure out
現在，有時你確實需要做一些實驗來找出
where that break point is, but it makes life very easy.
斷點在哪裡，但它讓生活變得非常簡單。
to do a responsive design once you have this layout all set up correctly.
一旦你正確設定了佈局，就可以進行響應式設計了。
Now after we've talked about flex and
在我們討論了 flex 和
grid and sometimes those are not the best options.
網格，有時這些並不是最佳選擇。
then we can resort to absolute and relative positioning as a secondary choice.
這時，我們可以將絕對定位和相對定位作為次要選擇。
Absolute is very powerful because you can place it anywhere on the screen and it's...
絕對定位非常強大，因為你可以把它放在螢幕上的任何位置，而且...
pretty self-explanatory what to do with it, but...
絕對定位的作用不言自明，但是...
Of course, like I mentioned, should be a secondary option.
當然，就像我提到的，絕對定位應該是次要選擇。
And a lot of times you use absolute in combination with relative.
很多時候，你會把絕對值和相對值結合起來使用。
So absolute and relative positioning are not so common to be using when you're
所以絕對定位和相對定位並不常用。
dealing with regular enterprise level applications, whether it's
在處理常規的企業級應用程式時，無論是
e-commerce or an admin dashboard, a lot of times those are very structural and it has
電子商務或管理儀表盤，很多時候這些應用程式都是結構性的，而且具有很強的對稱性。
A lot of symmetry.
很多對稱性。
When you're dealing with design websites.
在處理設計網站時
like design agencies or landing pages that are extremely fancy though like
比如設計公司或著陸頁，雖然它們非常花哨，比如
ones you would see on this particular website, AWW.
你會在 AWW 這個網站上看到。
Awards.com where they're very design based.
Awards.com上看到的那樣，它們非常注重設計。
For example, like this page.
例如，像這個頁面。
like this particular website and you have elements that are
就像這個特殊的網站，你的元素是
positioned in very unconventional locations.
定位在非常規的位置。
This is where you would use absolute and relative positioning.
這就是使用絕對定位和相對定位的地方。
because it is very hard to do flex when you have items that are
因為當你的專案一般都是對角線型別的排列，或者它們是奇數時，就很難做到彈性定位。
generally in diagonal type formations or they're kind of scattered
一般都是對角線型別的排列，或者它們有點分散
throughout the entire website.
整個網站。
Now aside from using
除了使用
Position absolute and relative for placing items in very tricky situations.
絕對定位和相對定位來在非常棘手的情況下放置專案。
like we've seen in that designer website.
就像我們在設計師網站上看到的那樣。
There is a very common occurrence of using position relative.
還有一種非常常見的情況是使用相對位置。
absolute for placing items on top of another item.
絕對位置用於將專案置於另一個專案之上。
So if you take a look at this card, right?
所以，如果你看看這張卡片，對嗎？
we have these two buttons that are placed on top of this box.
我們有兩個按鈕放在這個盒子的頂部。
And the way we do this is we set this entire box to be positioned
我們的做法是將整個框設定為相對位置。
relative.
相對位置。
We also set the image as the child of this entire box.
我們還將圖片設定為整個框的子項。
but we have another box that represents a position of
但我們還有另一個方框，它的位置是
Absolute.
絕對位置。
And that is positioned bottom.
它的位置是底部。
of 10% with the left of 0 and that gives us
為 10%，左側為 0，這樣我們就有了
this particular box element right here.
這個特定的框元素。
By doing so,
這樣一來
We have a very common pattern where we can set the parent
我們有一個非常常見的模式，可以將父元素設定為
with a position of relative and a child of position absolute.
父元素的位置為相對位置，而子元素的位置為絕對位置。
for any items that we want to place on top of another.
這樣，我們就能將父元素設定為相對位置，而子元素則設定為絕對位置。
And this is another situation over here in this...
這裡還有另一種情況...
carousel we can place this item using a parent a position relative on the entire
旋轉臺中的另一種情況，我們可以將這個專案的父項設定為相對位置，而子項設定為絕對位置。
higher carousel and then child for this particular item over here.
更高的旋轉木馬上，然後為這裡的這個特定專案設定子位置。
Another example can be seen here in this element over here with this image.
另一個例子是這裡的圖片元素。
and this outline border that's behind it.
和它後面的輪廓邊框。
And finally, in another example over here.
最後，這裡還有一個例子。
what I'm doing with this particular text that's in the background.
我在做什麼？
We need that text to follow this original over here.
我們需要讓這段文字跟上這裡的原文。
so that once we move it, this...
這樣一旦我們移動它，這個...
Big Tex is following Evo Jim.
大特克斯就會跟著埃沃-吉姆
So the way to do that is that we are setting
因此，我們要將
the parent element again to relative.
父元素為相對元素。
and a child element.
和一個子元素
that is using a selector called before.
使用一個名為 "之前 "的選擇器
again and setting that to be absolute and we position this
再次將其設定為絕對元素，然後我們將其定位
a little to the top above it.
在其上方一點。
and positioning it a little to the left so we start from over here instead of on
並將其向左定位一點，這樣我們就可以從這裡開始，而不是在這個軸上。
this axis.
軸。
And as you can see, absolutely
正如你所看到的，絕對
Absolute and relative positioning are generally used as a secondary option especially for
絕對定位和相對定位通常作為次要選項使用，尤其是對
functional and application type websites.
功能和應用程式型別的網站。
When it comes to designer-like websites, then you would use it.
當涉及到設計師類網站時，你就會使用它。
way more frequently but a lot of times you are
但很多時候你是
developing on more of a functional application.
開發的更多是功能性應用程式。
and in those cases you use relative and absolute positioning as a
在這種情況下，您可以將相對定位和絕對定位
combination and in sparing
和絕對定位相結合，並在不使用
use it.
使用。
And there you go, this is the most comprehensive CSS layout
就是這樣，這是我做過的最全面的 CSS 佈局
video I've ever done and I wanted to follow the step-by-step process so you have a foundation
影片，我想按照步驟一步一步來，這樣你就有了一個基礎
or structure for your CSS layouts.
或結構。
because a lot of people don't teach this fundamental.
因為很多人都不教這種基本的 CSS 佈局方法。
approach to CSS instead they just go through and
的方法，而只是透過
find little things that they want to change instead of setting up the foundation.
找到他們想修改的小地方，而不是打好基礎。
Anyways, like, comment, subscribe.
總之，請點贊、評論、訂閱。
See you next time.
下次見。